<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: mobile | Get Into This]]></title>
  <link href="http://getintothis.com/blog/categories/mobile/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://getintothis.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-02T19:02:17-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://getintothis.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ramin B.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fix blurry images in emails viewed on retina devices]]></title>
    <link href="http://getintothis.com/blog/2012/03/30/fix-blurry-images-in-emails-viewed-on-retina-devices/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-30T12:16:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://getintothis.com/blog/2012/03/30/fix-blurry-images-in-emails-viewed-on-retina-devices</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a super simple and easy fix for the blurry image problem you may have
noticed when reading emails on your retina capable device. Images and logos appear
all blurry and nobody likes that.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2012-30-03/email/email.png" title="Non-retina version" >
<img src="/images/2012-30-03/email/email@2x.png" title="Retina version" ></p>

<p>The trick is to create a 2x version of your image, but to set the width and height
values to the smaller version. For non-retina devices, you will get a higher res
image that is resampled down, which should look good in most cases. For retina capable
devices, the image is resampled up to its original higher resolution, but still remains
crisp.</p>

<p>I recommend doing this for just important images in your email, like your logo and
other icons that may have text in them, like share buttons, etc. Using this technique
on complex photos may result in less than desirable anti aliasing effects.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Triggering Zepto Tap Event using Click]]></title>
    <link href="http://getintothis.com/blog/2012/03/04/triggering-zepto-tap-event-using-click/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-04T21:10:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://getintothis.com/blog/2012/03/04/triggering-zepto-tap-event-using-click</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This one will come in handy if you are testing/debugging your mobile website on a Desktop browser (i.e. Safari, Chrome) with a custom User-Agent set and are utilizing the <code>tap</code> event provided by <a href="http://zeptojs.com/">Zepto JS</a>.</p>

<p>The issue with binding the <code>tap</code> event is that you cannot trigger them with a mouse click. And we all know that debugging on simulator and emulators is a pain in the ass, so hopefully this little code snippet will save you some time.</p>

<p>```javascript
(function($) {</p>

<pre><code>// only do this if not on a touch device
if (!('ontouchend' in window)) {
    $(document).delegate('body', 'click', function(e) {
        $(e.target).trigger('tap');
    });
}
</code></pre>

<p>})(window.Zepto);
```</p>

<p>You can use the same technique to trigger <code>touchstart</code> and <code>touchend</code> events using <code>mousedown</code> and <code>mouseup</code>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fixing HTML label tapping on iOS]]></title>
    <link href="http://getintothis.com/blog/2012/03/03/Fixing-HTML-label-tapping-on-iOS/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-03T15:54:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://getintothis.com/blog/2012/03/03/Fixing-HTML-label-tapping-on-iOS</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This one should be filed under the WTF category. Apparently, clicking/tapping on HTML
<code>&lt;label&gt;</code> in current versions (5.0 or older) of iOS Mobile Safari does not focus the corresponding
<code>form</code> element. Not sure if this a bug or done intentionally, but not only is it annoying, but also an accessibility issue.</p>

<p>There is a simple CSS "fix" for this, and it is seems to work pretty well across all form elements:</p>

<p><code>css
label { cursor: pointer; }
</code></p>

<p>Yeah, that's it. Go figure.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
